Jaehoon Jung

(631)838-1305 | hoon7589@gmail.com | https://jayjung98.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayjungnote/

PROFILE

Data Scientist who sees problems and makes decisions through data. Data scientists are necessary to have an attitude to solve everyday questions with data. I have the ability to define problems, find necessary data, analyze and solve them, and visualize and explain their conclusions. I studied basic coding and machine learning concepts through classes in school, and additionally, I personally studied machine learning through Python to improve coding skills. Also, through personal projects, I found a problem that I was interested in, experienced how to solve it, and developed my analytical thinking skills.

EDUCATION

Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY

January 2019 – December 2022

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and Statistics

Major GPA: 3.31/4.00

Relevant courses: Data analysis, Data mining, Operation research, Mathematical statistics, Database design

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, Java, C++

Software and Integrated Development Environments (IDEs): Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Microsoft

Visual Studio, Google Colab, RStudio, Eclipse, MS Acess

Languages: English – proficient, Korean - native

PROJECTS

Rossmann Store Sales, Kaggle Competition (https:///www.kagle.com/competitions/)

- Computed and visualized important features.
- Computed the best prediction of this data.

Roan and Repayment, Kaggle Competition (https:///www.kagle.com/competitions/)

- Computed which factors impact on whether the loan is repaid or not.
- Visualized the result and provided the interpretation of the resulting values.

Mobile Data Classification, Kaggle

- Computed cross-validation-score of each data model.
- Compared and evaluated the performance of each the following models: logistic regression, decision tree classifier, random forest classifier, Ada boosting, and Gradient boosting decision tree.

Soccer Player Analyzing

- Interpreted players to scout from European league players and remove from team squad.
- Computed and visualized specific personal skills using computer software.

EXPERIENCE

Army at Republic of Korea, Sergeant, Honorable discharged

Goseong, Kangwon-do

• Served in the general outpost at Go-Seong.

January 2020 – August 2021

• Executed a mission to monitor and analyze the enemies.

ACTIVITIES

English Peer Tutoring for International Students, Member of Bridge Tutor

San Angelo, TX

• Provided fun student-led, language-learning environment.

August 2017 – December 2018

Korea Student Association, Member of Welfare

San Angelo, TX

• Provided opportunities to learn Korean culture and language.

August 2017 – December 2018

• Hold K-Pop concert for San Angelo people.

Korean Life Media, Data Collector

Stony Brook, NY

• Executed collect and design data for the monthly radio broadcast. August 2019 – December 2019